Gabriel Anderson

andgate.io

github.com/andgate Ω linkedin.com/in/andgate Ω

Objective

Highly skilled developer with 2 years of industry experience and 15 years of independent practice, seeking a frontend developer role where I can apply my ideation, relator, and strategic strengths, alongside my broad range of technical skills, to build awesome software that makes a difference in the world.

Experience

Clearwater Analytics

Seattle, WA

Software Development Engineer

Apr. 2022 - Present

- Contributed to the development of the frontend for a high-profile internal company web application as a member of a high-performing team.
- Effortlessly leveraged my prior experience and knowledge in frontend development to rapidly attain expert proficiency in Angular and RxJS.
- Provided mentorship to developers at varying levels of experience and proficiency.
- Championed the establishment of a comprehensive set of written team coding standards and best practices.

SMART Technologies

Seattle, WA

Frontend Software Developer

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Served millions of customers on a frontend team responsible for supporting and expanding product capacity of the company's core solution, SMART Learning Suite Online.
- Built and deployed projects using TeamCity, working closely with DevOps team to ensure projects were integrated into a large final product.
- Designed and developed an Android overlay widget manager, written in Kotlin with an MVVM architecture, powered by Kotlin Flow.
- Decomposed a bloated widget framework into a set of packages as NPM monorepo using Lerna, to enable students to use the framework.
- Collaborated as a member of the winning team in a company hackathon, wherein we created a WebRTC video communications feature for our flagship application.

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Undergraduate Directed Research

Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Under Dr. Arne Leitart, explored theories to develop more a efficient, parameterized approximation algorithm for the (Connected) r-Domination problem for unweighted and undirected graphs.
- New theories were explored on whiteboard and paper exclusively.

Education

Central Washington University

Ellensburg, WA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics Graduated Magna Cum Laude Sept. 2017 - Mar. 2019

3.7 GPA

Projects

CoolScript

github.com/andgate/coolscript

• Lambda calculus interpreter and repl written in typescript with a react frontend.

solid-orbit

github.com/andgate/solid-orbit

• Published NPM package with solid-js hooks and components that provide an orbit-js data-layer.

Mandelbulb Explorer

github.com/andgate/mandelbulb

- Mandelbulb explorer written in c++ and glsl, using SFML to provide interactivity.
- Signed-distance fields were used to render the 3d mandelbulb fractal.

Skills

- Languages:
 - o Proficient: Javascript, Typescript, CSS, HTML, JSON, Java, Kotlin, C, C++, Haskell
 - Familiar: C#, Swift, Python, GLSL
- Frameworks: Node, React, Vue, Angular, Solid, RxJS, Kotlin Flow, OpenGL
- Methodologies: Scrum, Clean, OOP, FP
- Technologies: Android, Git, NPM, Webpack, Babel, Lerna, Docker, Bash, Emacs, VSCode, NixOS